all right welcome everyone it is April
2nd
2025 and this is active stream number
11.1 and I'll begin with a GitHub push
looking forward to everyone's
updates and ideas and questions in the
chat this should be an interesting
Stream So the title is April agents
bring May simulations open Manis RX and
fur. JL and agent laboratory I have a
few things prepared a few software
implementation we can play around with
also some topics to explore not sure how
any of the demos will go live however
it's the hope that a few things will be
pretty interesting and we can fix and
explore along the way so April agent
Spring May simulations or as Alexander
just pointed out April agents may bring
simulations there are many exciting
developments and advancements in the
multi-agent synthetic intelligence
systems space right now in a pretty
broad sense shortterm medium-term all
the
terms let's explore a few articulating
complimentary interesting kinds of
multi-agent Frameworks autonomous
Frameworks look at different ways of
looking at what makes agentic what kinds
of systems engineering are being done
within and among the agents all these
kinds of orchestration questions looking
where we're at instantaneously in April
2025 and more
broader so um there will be some jumping
around since some of the pieces take
different amounts of time to to load or
play out so again I'm not sure what
exactly will come
through that'll be part of the fun
though um on all of these branches I've
been having
some interesting times
there are three cursor
windows
open so starting with the two
llm type
models right now is running in this
terminal the work of Samuel schmidgall
agent
laboratory I'll read the overview agent
laboratory is an end
and autonomous research workflow meant
to assist you as the human researcher
towards implementing your research ideas
agent laboratory consists of specialized
agents driven by large language models
to support you through the entire
research workflow from conducting
literature reviews and formulating plans
to executing experiments and writing
comprehensive
reports this system is not designed to
replace your creativity but to
complement it enabling you to focus on
ideation and critical thinking while
automating repetitive and time intensive
tasks like coding and dentation by
accommodating varying levels of
computational resources and human
involvement agent laboratory aims to
accelerate scientific discovery and
optimize your research
productivity um this has an Associated
paper describing more so I got it to
work
initially output a really awesome 17
page paper images equation
I have the PDF around then I started
modifying it trying to get more logging
get more access to
it uh and kind of went too far and now
I've just pulled back to the main branch
that they've provided and just to show
this experiment while this one's running
and then we'll see how long it takes
hopefully it'll finish within the stream
um this yaml file which they provide
some initial examples of
I made a
variance that um has the following
sections copying it over with the
control I know write a new Yo compliant
file that has this
semantics the goal is to develop a
partially observable marov decision
process PDP implementing active
inference that is in a thermal
homeostatic setting so the kind of the
classic air conditioner do nothing
heater
temperature the API key for open AI is
put here and the
uh model is provided for the llm backend
and the review I guess separately
language here's different stages so I
found that when larger numbers were used
there were some interruptions I don't
know if that was because of stepping
away from the computer so these are
relatively
low levels of steps but it'd be
conceivable and interesting to see what
happens when literature review is huge
numbers or or what happens there how to
use a structured knowledge base for
literature
review um it's also possible to run
multiple labs in parallel then there's
these solvers
steps I wonder if that will throw an air
later we'll
see um these solver
steps which are described in the mle
solver and the paper
solver load an existing save and to
compile all the way on through the latc
PDF output and then this copies over the
notes format
and it's doing a pretty
multi-staged
effort uh the package setup did have a
few other packages that on my computer I
needed to set up but was pretty easy to
get through those with helper cursor 2
and get uh the virtual environment and
at least get it along the way using the
API key so this is pretty cool and uh
again keeping with this sort of just
snapshot there I'm I'm sure with
slightly different setups or just
different settings these are all really
functional I'm just showing how they're
running for me at this moment and uh
hopefully coming across some useful
outputs um but big
picture agent laboratory really cool and
partnering it in this sort of
multi-agent autonomous agent llm type
coordination uh in in the second window
we have open
Manis so I'll read the
description manace is incredible but
open Manis can achieve any idea without
an invite
code it's a simple implementation so we
welcome any suggestions contributions
and feedback enjoy your own agent with
open
Manis so look at the uh demo
here's videoing into
their
setup
describing the
task basically carrying out this task
within the repo that it's running from
so here
um there was I I started with a request
write a research report on Davis
California and I output this after 20
steps but it popped up a
browser um and now running a enhanced
version to see if it's possible to get a
longer
report um so it could just be how I'm
running it or setting it up it could but
just sort of conceptually we'll look at
the architecture of how it's set up even
if nothing to impressive comes from it
and uh those will be the two llm
type
[Music]
um processes
running here we are back in the PDP
research review writing code
writing
[Music]
um we'll see if we if we can tell what
the output but there are subtasks
um to what extent these are explicitly
described or to what extent there's an
initial uh plan or hierarchical plan
formulation how many steps that's taken
in how General the prompting all those
kinds of
things a lot of degrees of
freedom just
um seeing how it works here is just you
know interesting and then also again
open manace where here let's start this
one again with a
new but did it even
result
let's try to improve the
logging on open Manis then we'll go to
the third window which is the RX infer
do jail
given this type of
quote successful
output we ensure we are capturing all
outputs of tool use
better and
enabling running tools more
intelligently in order
to
achieve
sequential incremental
improving
outputs General
case all right and then the third
window is going to be the RX and fur. JL
example Bulls repo so here's the open
Manis now in the third window will be a
par repo for RX and fur which
is uh under some very interesting and
good open- source
development as part of this growing
interesting RX andur ecosystem including
also recently RX environments not going
to be probably covered here and also
this recent RX infer server so opening
up the possibility for different
languages to use API calls into these RX
infer type pipelines through their their
server and uh this might connect with
some general topics and multi-agent just
depends on what people write in the chat
and where these tools sort of take
us okay
using cursor
48 using for the most part Claude
[Music]
3.7 agent
mode all right started with the GitHub
push and let's just check on each of
the uh ongoing language model
uh
windows
then look to some of these recent
examples from RX and fur including how
they integrate with neural networks and
see if we can generalize that or connect
that also to these llm type
methods
um and yeah see where the different work
products from these more llm tool use
agents where that gets us and where we
get with okay here we
go
yep Mily Max
steps let's just do one Max of
everything so that it happens
from all the
stages
okay I'm going to um make a new API
key to put into this
moving it off screen so I can put in
this API key this way and save the
file so that'd be one way I thought of
modifying it having
a uh environment file or other method
for the
API lot of flexibility with which llm
and how to call it so that could just be
one thing and then here's okay so let's
run that
again AI lob repo is the script and then
it looks to the location of the Amo
file so
AI lab
repo all right looking at it while it
sets up gives a different language
default model maybe overridden
um the laboratory workflow is a 400 line
500 line method the archive
agent here's the argument that parses uh
or argument parsing for the
yaml parsing AML and then main for the
main logic of this main script that's
now playing out
here sets the llm
backbone determines whether it's in
human mode or not we can try that look
at the Amo and flip that value compile
PDF go from the latac pl text all the
way through at least trying to compile
the PDF uh load in previous workspace if
there are parallel Labs what to do in
exception uh
failure whether there's a archive
research agent
and the indices of the lab then there's
those limits on each of those steps
number of times to iterate through these
different
steps
um and how to
parallel getting the API keys from the Y
whether the open AI key or the Deep SE
key
has a logic for if it's in the human
interactive type
mode uh asking questions or whether it
uses
the uh yaml
information
language human and loop mode possibility
for different stages to have different
human in or on the
loop agent models which llm to use for
different
phases here it looks like this is a set
sequence of phases it could be specified
in a ton of different
ways uh parallelism
instructions some exception
Clauses checklist practical make a
better config system yaml advancements
make the ability to have agent build on
top of the research run agent labs in
parallel not sure if that's to do or
what was done um so this is going to
keep running hopefully we will not hit
that same error um should be a little
faster but it still might be a couple
minutes on that one all right now to
this
one so something was happening in
the open manace
um but we asked cursor in the agent mode
to enhance our ability to to understand
because the the
um the research report was not very long
so maybe just it's handled differently
with the database and the shared State
and and this is an example of kind of a
classic and and uh durable
type of tradeoff in multi-agent
modeling different kinds of
information uh
interactions ranging from this just kind
of informally implicit multi-agent Hub
and spoke type computational
architecture um if not Bas graph where
there's a niche that different agents
read and write from and this can be uh
in certain digital settings and even
probably some physical ones too
describe the
uh possible uh layouts of how to
organize shared
State
uh in cont cont with where there can be
direct interactions like interactions
among nestmates as well as with the
shared
environment and in the context of uh
doing these computational agents it is
like what is being transi what is being
remembered and modified how where's that
statistical updating of a probability
distribution like the RX and fur side of
things um whereas it some other kind of
model update where is it context for a
language model or
um to what extent is is that
update private within that agent uh
carried like sort of like a nestmate
level memory to what extent is it
accessible by different processes and it
kind of just ends up um being just in
uh some particular way that's very
situational so this is just showing a
few of the tools and hopefully with
people's uh comments or or suggestions
let's just see how many minutes it takes
to look into a few different functions
or at least
connect H how certain
uh package analyzes this connect that to
um
uh ways we can integrate amongst these
different Frameworks so okay now we have
um agent laboratory is running in the
first
one open Madness we ask for these
improvements now run the
improved open
Manus
that so sometimes there's a really
obvious way or an entry point um and I
think good code-based design can go a
long way I know there's a lot of cool
work being done with the cursor rules
and the MDC
files a as well as the mCP server calls
those are all things to uh look into but
even at a a code base of this
level sometimes it's a little bit hard
to even know uh which which script to
run or which entry point so sometimes
it's even useful just to ask in the
agents on the right side to even write
that as it as it needs to be and also to
update that experience like okay I don't
want to do any terminal uh extra
arguments just make it so that this
works
um so let's let cursor work on that
while we look on to
the
third of the three um modeling
approaches the RX and
fur
Okay so the RX infer examples repo is
maintained by the reactive base
organization um lazy Dynamics
fellas and what I have in the doxology
Fork is a another folder called
support and right now it has a few two
scripts there's setup.
JL which is at least a starting point
for setting up the packages and and
gives a a scaffold for adding other pack
packages that you might want to install
or something like that and then
importantly the notebooks to
scripts
script so this can be run from here with
Julia notebooks to scripts the file name
Julia space the file
name and takes the
documents that are in the original
repo the example
folder there's
different um folders within
examples but in the uh this script
converts those into a matching scripts
folder so we will look at uh two or
maybe more of
these
script uh analoges of some RX and for
examples um they're a little bit more
flexible to work with it's possible to
break them out into multiple
components and some of them probably run
a little smoother in the notebook
setting uh but by and large they uh all
work
to with just a a few tweaks or ordering
changes so we'll look at some that that
are already uh some variants have been
made of and then just drone or um some
other interesting one let's let's
explore it
okay agent laboratory
continuing
um cursor Improvement of open
Manis
proceeding on this side
so it's like the their agent
orchestration their micros service um
process orchestration all all all these
really
Advanced um services and software
perplexity
Etc pretty interesting how they how they
do it and surface it so we leave that
going and wait for it to complete while
looking at the RX andur
uh
examples so um first example will be uh
the
recently
written recurrent switching linear
dynamical system this one uh where we're
getting to with it just to sort of put
the um and this this is not not to say
that this is perfectly statistically
optimized just to show some of the
expression capacities of where where we
can model and then from there figuring
out um is rx
[Music]
infer where where might it be at
different stages in different
projects ranging from uh a uh
statistical power type systems modeling
intuition skeleton
scaffold probabilistic
layer all all the way on through
complimenting and Inter integrating uh
with different machine learning
pipelines like where where and how my
and what if probabilistic modeling in in
fusion with some more dynamical systems
type
time series
modeling neural networks
llms uh all these different
architectures of statistical
models it it's
um where how do we compose useful
systems for variously more on the
recognition Direction doing a latent
State inference from noisy data which is
a commonality of of the models that that
will be looked at so in this um you or
using it to recognize latent States from
noisy data Andor generating
predictions from Laten State estimates
so here in this setting there's a a
noisy sequence of
measurements and at a a
discrete layer there there's a switch
between two regimes one and
two where the second discret state has
this higher amplitude
oscillation and so there's a switching
between these two
modalities and we explore how hard is it
to have a three-state switch model um so
at the sort of faster layer there's this
time series
interpolation uh Auto regressive type
model
which we can look at with the app model
statements and then at the slower level
there's this linear um and then the
other example that has uh a lot to do
with this first example
is um uh three-dimensional in time Loren
attractor with noisy sampling coming
from it and in this uh
example integrating neural networks with
flux
JL there's a two-step process that has a
lot to do with the continuous time time
series interpolation and the slower
switching model here at the first level
there's the learning of a a a
statistical model of the
Loren
attractor State
space using a flock neural network in
Julia then
probabilistic parameters according to a
at model statement in RX and fur are
used to
model certain
distributions of that train neural
network so it's like a common theme is
so here's now the three dimensions of
the Lorenz
tractor so the blue line is the
[Music]
inferred from the actual basian
posteriors uh reflected by these
matrices and their change through
time
um in terms of now possibly
miscalibrated it's not to say that this
makes this an accurate assessment and I
think there's a lot to um to to look at
there but these are posterior estimates
that in certain conditions or situations
or data sets can give give better
estimates and other
Alternatives that have for example in
this situation on this dimension for the
lorens is a uh parametric estimate in
terms of a mean and a
variance of this posterior distribution
constrained to the gaussian family of
just mean and variance parametric
statistics uh rather and that can be
computation Ally implemented
typed simulated
Etc in in a number of ways with an
explicitly distributional
analytical nature knowing that it's
going to be this normal
distribution now if the underlying state
is is
bodal then there are all the sorts of
attractor States depending on where it
goes and how the optimization unfolds
like whether it over disperses to
capture the mean or whether it sharpens
to go onto the median like a local
Optima so but all that being said it
gives this parametric estimate in terms
of an explicit mean and
variance which can be used in any
statistical method for what would
otherwise be distributed throughout the
weights of like the neural network with
many parameters needing to be simulated
for inference whereas with these more
distilled summary statistics on the
posteriors it can be compressed to a
very small um scale even though as as uh
more parameters are added it the fit
might be better because interal Network
might be able to to know that there was
some more structure than just the the
two parameters that allowed to be
specifying this distribution so that's
kind of the um topic that I think in in
a lot of ways regardless of what the
agent orchestration layer
is which this is giving us some windows
into there sort of this orthagonal
analytical or behavioral scientific
framing of this information
environment using
these
uh using probability
distributions to model
outputs of other
models some places in motifs where that
could be like parameter on parameter on
parameter or it could be llm on llm on
llm all these different
chains of uh of interactions
between models that are more
like let's have a ton of parameters and
try to interpolate a
function and pick the size of the model
out of convenience or or compute like
why 7 billion parameter language model
because maybe uh just in the short term
it's easier to fork or use the the
training methods that are known
or whatever it may be but use a certain
given large number of parameters choose
your own or some other common number and
and then hope that there's enough
degrees of freedom and in the curriculum
of the
training that it's it's
uh that it interpolates and learns the
space and does the good function
approximation and and you don't have to
do an analytical description of like the
information space yet it can learn a lot
of the important structural features um
it whereas for example a explicit
probability
distribution over
Words which is kind of has a functional
encoding in the the larger
um many parameter type like llm type
learn all the statistical associations
including higher order ones among
different textual inputs
and then learn the the specifics of that
from from the training data
was but spe letting those weights and
coefficients amongst all of the billions
of
parameters become fit through the
training
uh in this app model type RX
infer um
setting and then also in in the textbook
group there was
um one person was interested in posture
so we modified it so maybe we can modifi
another of gray is the
proception noisy signaling coming from
the body then there's the perceived and
the
actual
posture embodying the the uh
switching and constraints
chaotic uh dynamical underlying system
with a lorens being like the transition
between two different modes this could
be like seated biomechanics and standing
biomechanics um or different uh the the
Loren or other attractor systems could
be sampled
from uh or or mixtures of systems could
be
uh model multiple ways of modeling the
generative process that's giving rise to
these noisy observations doesn't have to
be just fit with
Loren
um but similar theme
um let's look at the app model that
defines the probabilistic part of it
here's the state space
model which can be uh in certain places
and
ways run in situations where the larger
neural network might not necessarily be
able to operate like it all the
variables that have to be stored within
a semantics of this being the arguments
passed to this
SSM model the can be
interpretable true variance posterior
estimates um explicit composition of
different statistical
distributions um the there's more to it
for uh the for logging and for
coordinating the calls and the
orchestration of how these app models
get used in The rhythms of of other API
calls and and program Logics but the app
model is kind of the this statistical
kernel that is the one that gets parsed
and and rendered and and uh used as the
underlying declarative base graph for
the RX Ander model that then gets a
certain scheduling of either the
standard sort of Passover all of the
nodes and update them in this order uh
imperative style update this and then do
this and then do this and then do that
and then to what extent that that that
uh
scheduling of updating strategies on
that base
graph that is what reactive message
passing in principle kind of opens the
degrees of freedom around so it's like
well this can be under this timing this
one can be triggered by this or react to
this ra rather than the whole graph
being either updated sort of in a uh
sweep or just in any given
fixed um for Loop type computational
execution uh approach to that
distribution so this is the joint
generative model of the state space
model inferred from from the neural
network so the of
the uh from the
noisy Loren
data so um let's check the other okay
agent laboratory still writing
cursor
finished commands to
run to run and log the demos
written hello Zig
train the neural network on the Loren's
noisy
data so using just a ton of parameters
throwing it at the
problem training the neural
network okay
test sequential
tools this is what we
get there should be at full
function logging of
the vest sequentially
improved actual plans
documents research
outputs Etc
logged and enacted by this system
agent laboratory still
going okay that was the neural network
learning the neural network and then
describing parameters of a
um of a
uh specific app
model so those were two of the um but
let's look at a new one like drone
Dynamics all
right so hav't done this one let's see
what it what it results let's let's see
what it looks like so this is in
advanced
examples drone Dynamics
notebook drone do
GI all right
awesome drone dog GIF 2D
drone drone 3D multi
looks awesome so if we can recapitulate
this and start extending it a little bit
and understand the app model add in some
logging look at some other
visualizations um adapt it to foraging
and the honeybee or something like that
like there's there's so many um so this
is just as as we watch these three
processes play out which again under
under total
no May make it happen and do
it comprehensively now these you know
two weeks later the level of function
could be I guess somehow deteriorated in
some way but considering just for the
most part largely improved a lot of the
things that I'm doing certainly someone
with different or or more development
experience Andor another more advanced
version of
[Music]
cursor that could just iterate a few
more times uh or a little bit better
with coding so it's it's pretty wild um
and and I'm I'm excited to see like what
people do with uh it's not just Vibe
coding it's it's more different than
that um I think in in ways or at least
it can be okay quick scan over the Drone
example
these examples demonstrate the use of RX
infer for motion planning the animation
show the inferred trajectories from
probabilistic inference rather than
simulated
executions for more realistic
simulations especially in the 3D drone
example the model would need to be
extended with reactive environment # RX
environments that responds to the
drone's actions during plan execution if
you're interested in collaborating on a
more realistic implementation please
open a discussion and let's work on it
together and that links to to a
discussion on reactive
base okay let's quickly look through
it import
packages environmental features like
gravity physics of the mass inertia
radius and force limit properties of the
drone aerial properties of the
Drone state the
Drone Vector of these
variables model
specification location State
transition based upon this declarative
statistical
style graphical model specification for
the Drone model that's going to get
rendered up and done all these ways with
the RX infer using the app model
macro planning Loop included inside of
the app model Macro for the time
Horizon
involving something like rolling out the
prior onc consquences of
action physics
related with the state transition
[Music]
s but how does it select
action then uh probabilistic
inference not sure what unscented means
here but some kind of state transition
approximator this is an interesting
function I I think it'll be like is it
really this easy to make a wrapper
function called move to
Target if so that feels like a really
high level function even for a
3D
nav system to to be able just to be like
move the Target and have it have
this um
definiteness that that's that'll be
interesting to look at how that
happens uh initial condition
specification plotting of the Drone
animation of the
Drone so hopefully getting the script
running will get us
to understand
um all these different
visualizations and maybe make a few new
visualizations just using the script and
and generalizing it from there let's
check on the llms then continue with the
Drone all right agent
Laboratory continues
to use
this um we had some really fun
interesting discussions in the Discord
so like just taking a little snippet
here these are llm
costs um
postto let's take a fresh perspective in
developing our PDP model for thermal
homeostasis focusing on agile design
that prioritizes user Centric features
while maintaining strong mathematical
Integrity here a newly formulated plan
that emphasizes practical user
engagement and theoretical
robustness three action states of the
PDP five continuous
band uh on a on a Continuum making a
discrete State space 5 option Laten
space so it's laying out different
aspects
certain parts of it are repeating things
it could just be logging it could be
could be other ways to do the prompt
engineering like this just looks like
it's repeating things right
now maybe it's actually asking if we're
ready or
something but it's yeah I I think
that'll interrupt let's see okay
something is happening
let's leave that highlighted return to
it here looks like the cursor
agent make the updates and run
it and fun it
okay um back to the
Drone
um so we looked at the readme for the
Drone this is in the scripts folder
which basically takes this The Notebook
that we looked at with the inner spersed
comments and pulls out just the Julia
code so right click on the code open an
integrated
terminal pretty cool that cursor enables
even one computer to do
this
stuff and and a lot of externalities on
the compute so so you know local there's
a lot of cool ways to do this um but
using multiple different Cloud resources
like this hope that it's all useful and
relevant in the broader service of of
living and and
computation start out with just running
it as it first
converts Julia drone
Dynamics it may need a slight reordering
or it could just be like my environment
or we'll
see
[Music]
um one feature that comes up a lot in
the um RX and
fur group and and then and learning
about it is just like this
very Julia ask you usage of statistical
variables very close to as they
are
analytically isomorphically uh I mean
ideally and and um learning the syntax
of what is allowed sort of in in in
plausibility where is it speculative
realism
distributional uh specification
where and how does the does the current
ability to make different kinds of nodes
and Implement different kinds of edges
in RX and fur which could be more uh
general or robust in the future I'd
expect so just from an open source
software development side like what
kinds of app
models will what kinds of statistical
Behavior arise
from what kinds of Logics and functions
like go to Target are
being
um put within the app model what's in
the logic of updating and calling
different nodes there's just a lot of
interesting areas and uh spaces for for
taking these functional examples and if
if and being clear about where where are
we having problems in implementing these
examples like I don't expected to run
the first
one because it was a notebook but then
it hopefully is just one or a few
prompts away and then we can start
taking these things apart looking at
making more
logging um testing different variants
please update this to run it just hangs
it was
converted from
notebook break it up
out into
any separable
modules properly invoked if you think it
best okay it looks possibly
let's just see what happens if we say
move
ahead
okay let's
this one seems to be hanging
again so here one one affordance that
they sort of point two is new
chat so this is back to open
manace here is
what we get now use a chain
of open manace calls
and Tool use on incrementally writing
reports and doing
dispatch of document writing
then stitching together as editor at the
end
okay this is still happening so that
took
1,800
seconds okay it's loading
some
information this is like this is getting
into the
um yeah so stuff is coming
out but this is a one of the big open
questions that hopefully we won't get
too off the rails with in this with the
tools but even with the um and perhaps
even especially with the H Hazard and
just open source grabbing these tools
but even if it were a much more well
orchestrated
documented
approach even that would be be an
especially important like what is really
being empowered in the environment that
I'm running this
in
um where are different kinds of real
consequences
possible it's
just
um it's pretty interesting and and how
does that relate to the actual technical
basis of what the model is and does and
how it's interpreted okay
move
some drone
core we can use perplexity to make a
drone core image
see if we can get the studio
[Music]
jii
okay yeah so in the time when it wrote
the 17 Page
PDF so it didn't output uh the other
discourses and but a lot of more stuff
was happening but it it just saved in in
the time that I previously ran this just
17 Page PDF on this thermal PDP model
and concept but it really did have
files like this
file partially
haphazardly outside of its uh Lane but
not
um not few files were were
made hugging phase data sets really may
be coming here there really were Python
scripts that did have some outputs and
some source code was written so we'll
see where where that goes and I think
that's another sort of General topic is
just file structure
handling to what extent should more
relational databases and uh General High
Performance databases and maybe they're
already being used in in in different
ways to make some of the handling of the
reference of these different system
components more
facilitated doing it locally like all of
these examples has a lot of
interpretability it's like very
Hands-On but for high reliability
there's some other methods but those
does have their own sort of tradeoffs so
okay so we got
open Manis being improved by cursor to
make more sequential incremental State
sharing amongst
runs um let's just run the
main this is
um uh let's let's run
this is the initialized
script activate the virtual environment
yes run open manness yes
okay
oh
okay okay drone
example March is
on pop out terminal
so it is
happening could be hanging in a really
useless
place
okay code
execution in the agent Laboratory test
train
split loading some data from hugging
face lab number two is the index of that
lab so it's like where I I don't know
where this is happening in the in the
cache so where do different files get
stored where does that get stored in
databases
Etc okay looks like some kind of error
but what what was very interesting to
see is this so hm this is
a just wasn't sure what level of code
this even was in terms of Errors
happening in certain
tasks blurring with written scripts
because the scripts for the
tasks are in this repo which also has
Eda access to these tools and to
cursor so it's just it's probably not
the um most crystallized High
reliability setting but it has this sort
of open-ended Evolution element with the
agent laboratory
especially um okay open Manis
common cursor
pathology let's let's let's do something
totally
different use the
open let's just start a new
chat fix
this so that main. pi
Works fully functionally as it
should
okay
okay RX infer drone model is running
post do just being post
dos 2D
okay while that's
running add more logging to the
outputting so we better with emoi
structuring understand and and can
report on the timing and resource uh
just timing of different
stages
okay so RX Ander at least is doing some
logging
here of running
the Drone Dynamics
simulation break out
the core
program spec and logic
flow from the
statistical description
of the G at model
stat
okay errors from Julia
so now with the errors from the logging
from it fix this and add more
there open
Manis okay now main is working all right
so here's what the open man is
functionality what just running the main
enter your prompt
I am in a live stream
on multi-agent
Dynamics
research and report on with five
paragraph
essays
and
code stories
about what kinds
of State ofth art methods it would make
sense
to
comprehensively
understand in April
2025 oh
already let's see what time it
is okay let the open
manace
repair still
writing PhD
dialogue now it's into the storying of
the um
all right back to the
Drone working on drone
Dynamics so hopefully that even even
though I'll do about 10 or 15 more
minutes
[Music]
um these are all right in the zone of
just hit and
miss right now and so I'm just sort of
that's why I'm showing from a more reset
State um but I think people
can report back and and obviously we
will see um what is really
possible with making these systems a lot
more High reliability in in multiple key
ways
so okay so yeah this is coming from open
manace this is with the
browser so let's pop this out yeah
incredible okay it popped up this window
with these analysis
boxes brought
here is going to be the
terminal this is man is selecting these
tools is it the uh you know is it the
best possible way to look at this action
selection or you know how to interact
best with sites with the some many
degrees of freedom but that's a pretty
cool out outcome so let's let that
browse and and and consider the
watershed moment
while agent laboratory is writing the
thermal
PDP and now we have the improved
logging RX infer drone
form let's do
another
drone
script same total
functionality
with fewer
time steps
well let's just look
let let's reduce the number of time
steps
in our
simulation okay oh
add to
chat and fix this error
so here's the Step 11 so that's what
that was the chain of of tool use that
was leading to that website the news
website
okay all right it has popped
up family center.
met. looks like possibly SL Brazil in
Portuguese
unexpected but
okay okay grab attention again with
that paper continuing on in the open
AI variably
successful um modification using LLS M
of RX
infer
code so that's one one reason it's fun
to do the script first off it allows a
lot more articulation and separation
between different parts of the code
better logging for for when things are
not working it can break things too but
that's the helper script so as long as
they keep the main RX
infer examples notebook functional or or
similar reference models of
code then it's a lot easier to
regenerate functional scripts and start
modifying from
there yeah I'm going to do about 10
minutes
more so if anyone has any comments or
questions they want to have mentioned in
the last 10 minutes write
them okay let's look at how tool use
really output
okay running just 2D quick so let's see
if this will successfully save an
output it was working a little more
earlier on with the the numbers and the
outputs so let's see if we can at least
recover that if not save into but once
we have the
scripts and the ability to to modularly
break it out in pretty simple steps then
there can be different logging and
saving it can be okay well now just
deposit that Vector into this Matrix
form and then just keep on working from
there so there's a lot of ways to use
even just the um State space Clarity
that making these probabilistic models
can provide that's kind of the systems
modeling part that's that's always
really interesting so 15 Steps
deep possibly
just what did we even ask
for what time is
it Overkill right but
General so open man is probably not not
even pretending to be otherwise than
such seems like a little bit like less
of a functional version it's it's but
it's it's um a great
direction to
um at
least point in that
direction agent laboratory has the
associated
paper let's hope that it will finish in
the last
again things are happening with open
Mana so it has that sort of tool
architecture paper still writing over
there 16 out of 20 open
Manas drone error
yeah and also it's helpful to have
the notebook form available in the code
base so then it can be referenced say
okay this was working especially early
on yeah I feel that this will not finish
and render PDF but the the PDF that it
did render previously was
keeps like going to this
website let's see what one it opens
next the the the PDF
was styed probably one or two
times but then generally was rendering
totally
fine so they used a a bunch of different
methods it's really cool work
um yeah
multi-agent acto
blockprints where we've for for a few
years sort of with es and
flows talked a lot about these these
topics about uh approaches for cognitive
modeling ways to take procedural
approaches ontologically driven
approaches to to modeling connecting
that with data Integrity stuff like from
block science with different and other
requirements engineering
P3 these kinds of modeling
layers oh it detected that the browser
window is closed maybe that shouldn't be
done next
time let's see if it can fix the Drone
example in the next 7 minutes but if
anyone has any last
comments go for it
okay close that oh yeah the Drone
core images and perplexity not sure why
they kind of broke it out it was nice
when it was on that side
tab um gave a talk earlier
today and this was a one of the themes
was the two sides of this
coin natural foraging systems and
Engineering forging systems and
algorithms and this sort of
bidirectional relation this perspective
swap the systems as they are and the
empirical data the the inspiration they
provide and then also these computer
scientific more
engineered or more
mathematical uh models multi-agent
settings and in the ways that those are
kind of coming together giving all these
different optional for
modeling
okay see stunning s only accessible by
rail okay drone at least is started
up this one always looks like it's
halting but I think at these these
stages maybe when it runs the um paper
solver even just one time this could be
a lot faster probably with a
parallelized labs and with uh not just
this older laptop that I'm running this
from um this this seems like there's a
lot of
backend um possibilities and from the
requirements installation like there are
some packages so like huh wonder why
they're doing that and so it seems like
there's some pretty um Advanced methods
that are being used
sequentially and that was what I sort of
broke it trying to get
at and and but what I know will will be
part of it in in the bigger picture
is that kind of expressivity graphical
user
interface
from no to low to very medium and high
code High touch ways of working with
these
informations these are all just sort of
again halfhazard
archetypes and um they will already in
their own description of frictions
and just looking at functions here as
randomly assembled on the given
afternoon um and pointed to by these
repos and peers and sort of adjacent
from from this sort of concept there's
just a lot of space to think about how
how to get this to all work in whether
this is the best agent orchestration
framework or as several times I've just
built it from scratch with just a few
prompts or whether using some other
agent orchestration Frameworks in any
given moment that's that's a super
important question and I I hope that we
continue to develop down those lines and
stay
multiple
there um there's just sort of
overlapping and complimentary functions
that difference modeling approaches
can yield
and uh having the the modeling
capabilities connected with like
requirements engineering pattern
languages those kinds of features so
that there can be formal and natural
language um effective descriptions of
systems connecting that to the
compositionality of multi-agent
LM browser
type code writing and uh reviewing
improving of the code which at least the
first time that I got it to work it it
totally did do sequential code
Improvement and running I don't know
with what
resourcing it was running the code or
how it was getting to the outputs of the
code
um in terms of its workspace and all of
that but but but those are just the
questions um 20 steps or what what's the
right number of what compositions
content
empty so even though while while the
outputs are in many ways less impressive
than just one
perplexity um search might get
you it's about these
functionalities and different
composition
alties being more and more
accessible more
multimodal um part of larger
orchestration
Frameworks more open to calling and
receiving API calls and different
information measures on the input and
the output and the cognitive nature of
different
systems um that sort of low road High
Road um whether it's as
[Music]
systems uh must be for a given Observer
all these different ways that people
talk about the different um relational
modeling
stance and
pragmatism how that's all connecting
with just the ability to Vibe code and
uh make documentation
tests logging
functions a lot of different things that
okay this this finish
did it even save a file
maybe but it did do some browser opening
so okay goodbye open
Menace so now we have just in this last
minute see what happens we have the uh
agent
lab which does the and and and prior did
get some artifacts being
built of just multi-agent coordination
and the RX andur giving some issues for
the Drone example but was much easier to
move over to the script form for the
neural network and the recurrent uh
switching linear dynamical systems model
so thank you all hope that was
interesting Andor
useful not as much baseball and so on as
there could have been but say lovey so
thank you till next time bye